<?xml version="1.0"?>
<civs>
  <civ>
    <name>Aztecs</name>
    <primary>Eagle Warriors (Barracks)</primary>
    <support>Jaguar Warriors (Castle), Pikemen (Barracks), Arbalests (Archery Range)</support>
    <notes>Aztecs have very strong Eagle Warriors with their unique
    technology Garland Wars giving all their infantry +4 attack.
    Eagle Warriors are fast raiding units that excel against ranged
    and siege units, however they fall flat against other melee units.
    That's where your Jaguar Warriors (anti-infantry) and Pikemen
    (anti-cavalry) come in.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Berbers</name>
    <primary>Cavaliers (Stables) or Camels (Stables)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range)</support>
    <notes>Berbers have cheaper cavalry, so you should use this to your advantage. An army of 
    Cavaliers and Camels backed up by Skirmishers - to take care of those pesky Halberdiers -
     can go a long way.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Britons</name>
    <primary>Longbowman (Castle) or Arbalests (Archery Range)</primary>
    <support>Light Cavalry (Stables), Halberdiers (Barracks)</support>
    <notes>The Britons' claim to fame are their long-range archers, including their unique unit
    Longbowman and their Arbalests from the Archery Range. Light Cavalry to take care of enemy
    Skirmishers and Siege Units, and Halberdiers to take care of enemy Cavaliers/Paladins,
    which are the biggest counters to archers. Rain on 'em with your Longbowmen!</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Burmese</name>
    <primary>Arambai (Castle) or Battle Elephants (Castles)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Barracks), Halberdier (Barracks)</support>
    <notes>The Burmese has very good Battle Elephants. Their unique unitm, the Arambai, is very
    inaccurate at long range, so you have to put them very close (2 tiles away max) to the enemy
    to do damage. Since both the Arambai and the Battle Elephants are cavalry, the opposing
    civs will build Halberdiers and Camels to counter you. To kill Halberdiers, Skirmishers
    will do the trick. For Camels, your Halberdiers can take care of them.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Byzantines</name>
    <primary>Arbalests (Archery Range) or Cataphracts (Castle) or Paladins (Barracks)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Skirmishers (Archery Range), Camels (Stables),
    Hussars (Stables)</support>
    <notes>The Byzantines are kings of "trash" units, i.e. units that do not cost gold. These
    units are the Skirmishers, the Halberdiers, and the Hussar. Trash units for Byzantines
    cost less resources than other civs, except for Hussars.
    However, that means you should spend gold on more powerful units. The Byzantines unfortunately
    lack the final Melee Offensive upgrade at the Blacksmith (Blast Furnace), so their melee units
    deal less damage than other civs. The exception is their unique unit, the Cataphracts. The
    Cataphracts deal area of effect damage once the Imperial tech Logistica is researched at the
    Castle, meaning for every attack they will do an extra 5 damage to any nearby units. Cataphracts
    also deal bonus damage to infantry. The Byzantines also get fully upgraded Arbalests, so their
    Archery range units are strong. Combined either Arbalests and Cataphracts with their cheaper
    trash units as supporting units and the Byzantines can have a formidable military force.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Celts</name>
    <primary>Scorpions (Siege Workshop)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Woad Raider (Castle)</support>
    <notes>The Celts excel in Siege Workshop units, particularly the Scorpions and the Onagers.
    Onagers can do friendly fire damage though, thus they are a bit harder to use than
    Scorpions. Siege Workshops shred through archers and skirmishers, but they struggle against
    melee and other siege units. To take care of that, the Halberdiers can deal with any
    cavalry trying to get to your siege units, while the Woad Raiders can take care of opposing
    siege units.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <primary>Chu Ko Nu (Castle) or Scorpions (Siege Workshop)</primary>
    <support>Light Cavalry (Stables), Halberdiers (Barracks), Camels (Stables)</support>
    <notes>The Chinese have very good unique units in the Chu Ko Nu. They have less range than
    other archers, but they do significantly more damage, even to high pierce armor targets
    such as Rams. However, siege units such as Onagers will still pose a threat to the 
    low melee armored Chu Ko Nus. To kill siege units, go for Light Cavalry. To kill any
    cavalry that's trying to get to your archers, go for Halberdiers and Camels.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Ethiopians</name>
    <primary>Arbalests (Archery Range), Scorpions (Siege Workshop)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Hussars (Stables), Shotel Warrior (Castle)</support>
    <notes>Ethiopians have faster firing archers, thus you can use this advantage by making
    lots of archers. They also have very strong Siege units with their Imperial unique tech,
    Torsion Engine. You should have Hussars in front of your archers and siege units as a
    meat shield, while having Halberdiers to deal with any incoming Cavalry. Shotel Warriors
    get created very quickly, thus they can be used to defend against opposing Rams, 
    Skirmishers, and Halberdiers.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Franks</name>
    <primary>Paladins (Stables)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Halberdiers (Barracks), Throwing Axeman (Castle)</support>
    <notes>The Franks have one good unit, and that is the Paladin. Granted, they have the best
    Paladins in the game, so that should be something. They also get free Mill farm upgrades, so
    their Farms are very good (not as good as Slavs though). Paladins' biggest counters are
    Halberdiers and Camels. To take care of Halberdiers, go for Skirmishers. Your own Halberdiers
    take care of opposing Camels. However, your Skirmishers lack the final archer upgrades 
    in the Blacksmith, so they are not too strong. To combat this, if you have any extra gold,
    consider building Throwing Axemen to counter the Halberdiers.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Goths</name>
    <primary>Huskarls (Castles and Barracks once Anarchy is researched)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Hussars (Stables)</support>
    <notes>The Goths have the best infantry in the game because their infantry is cheaper and their
    Barracks work faster, especially after their Imperial tech Perfusion is researched. The
    Huskarls, their unique unit, can be created from the Goths' Barracks after their Castle Age tech
    Anarchy is researched. The Huskarls have very high pierce armor, making them excellent
    against archers and Scorpions. Huskarls are weak against cavalry and onagers. Halberdiers
    can handle cavalry, while the Hussars can handle onagers.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Huns</name>
    <primary>Paladins (Stables) or Cavalry Archer (Archery Range)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Hussars (Stables), Halberdiers (Barracks)</support>
    <notes>The Huns are a very aggressive civ, simply because they do not have to waste early
    resources on building houses. They have a great Stable, with their Stables working 20% faster.
    They also have cheaper Cavalry Archers if you opt to use them as the backbone of your
    military. If you opt to go for Paladins, go for Skirmishers to kill off the pesky Halberdiers.
    If you want to build Cavalry Archers, build some Hussars to take care of skirmishers and 
    siege. If you see opposing Camels, start making Halberdiers.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Incas</name>
    <primary>Kamayuk (Castle) or Eagle Warriors (Barracks)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Arbalests (Archery Range), Skirmishers (Archery Range)</support>
    <notes>Similar to the Aztes, the Incas are a Meso civ with strong infantry units. Their unique
    unit, the Kamayuk, is anti-cavalry, so if you build them you don't have to build any additional
    Halberdiers. Kamayuks are weak against opposing infantry and archers, so consider building
    Arbalests to kill infantry and Skirmishers to kill archers. </notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Indians</name>
    <primary>Imperial Camel (Stables)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Hand Cannoneer (Archery Range after Chemistry is
    researched at the University)</support>
    <notes>The Indians have one of the best camels in the game, them being the Imperial Camels.
    Camels are anti-cavalry, and Indian Camels are especially tanky thanks to their +1 Melee/
    +1 Pierce armor. Camels are weak against Archers and Halberdiers, both units that Skirmishers can
    counter. In the late game, Hand Cannoneer can also be used against Halberdiers since Hand
    Cannoneers get +10 attack against infantry.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Italians</name>
    <primary>Genoese Crossbowman (Castles)</primary>
    <support>Hussars (Stables)</support>
    <notes>The Italians have a great unique unit in the Genoese Crossbowman since these archers
    are anti-cavalry, thus they innately counter one of the archers' weakness. However, they are
    still weak to Skirmishers and Siege units, where you can use the Hussars to counter.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <primary>Arbalests (Archery Range) or Samurai (Castles), Trebuchets (Castles)</primary>
    <support>Light Cavalry (Stables), Halberdiers (Barracks), Skirmishers (Archery Range),
    Scorpions (Siege Workshop)</support>
    <notes>The Japanese have very great infantry (infantry attacks faster) and a complete
    Archery Range. They also have a complete Blacksmith tree, so any units they go for can be fully
    upgraded at the Blacksmith. Furthermore, they also have a complete Barracks, save for the
    Meso-only Eagle Warriors. Thus, you can either go for an army of mass Arbalests combined with
    Halberdiers and Light Cav, or you can go for Samurai (anti-unique unit), Halberdiers and
    Skirmishers, depending on the opposing army composition. If you have spare gold in the end
    game, Heavy Scorpions are also a good choice to counter opposing Archers. Lastly, the Japanes
    Trebuchets packs and unpacks faster, thus you can destroy a castle, pack your Trebuchet,
    and move it to destroy the next building much faster than any other civ.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Khmer</name>
    <primary>Scorpions (Siege Workshop) or Battle Elephants (Stables)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Halberdiers (Barracks), Light Cavalry (Stables)</support>
    <notes>Khmer has strong Battle Elephants and strong Scorpions after their Imperial tech
    Double Crossbow is researched. However, both units are gold-intensive, so you should
    pick only one of the two units to mass. Battle Elephants are very weak to Halberdiers and
    Monks, thus you'll need Skirmishers for Halberdiers and Light Cavalry for Monks. If you decide
    to mass Scorpions, go for Halberdiers to stop the opposing cavalry units.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Koreans</name>
    <primary>Towers, Castles, War Wagons (Castles)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Hussars (Stables)</support>
    <notes>Koreans have very strong towers and they have a bonus to stone mining, so consider
    building lots of Towers and Castles for defensive or offensive purposes (tower rushes come
    to mind). Koreans also have a good Archery Range and a great unique unit in the tanky
    War Wagons. War Wagons are considered Cavalry Archers and they are fairly slow, so 
    opposing cavalry can counter them, especially Camels. To counter this, make Halberdiers
    to kill opposing cavalry. Also, make Hussars to counter any opposing Skirmishers that try to
    kill your War Wagons.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Magyars</name>
    <primary>Paladins (Stables) or Cavalry Archers (Archery Range)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Halberdiers (Barrracks), Hussars (Stables),
    Magyar Hussars (Castle)</support>
    <notes>The Magyars have great cavalry as well as great cavalry archers. If you decide to
    mass Paladins, make Skirmishers to kill opposing Halberdiers and Halberdiers to kill opposing
    Camels. If you feel more like Cavalry Archers, go for Hussars to kill the Skirmishers and your
    unique unit Magyar Hussars to kill Siege. Note that if you want to make Magyar Hussars,
    consider researching the Castle age tech Mercenaries at the Castle so that your Magyar Hussars
    cost no gold.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Malay</name>
    <primary>Arbalests (Archery Range), Two-Handed Swordsman (Barracks)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Skirmishers (Archery Range)</support>
    <notes>Although Malay has access to the Battle Elephant, they do not have access to the
    2 final Blacksmith cavalry armor upgrades, thus making their cavalry line very very weak.
    Thus, you should focus on their fully upgraded Arbalests as well as their Two-Handed
    Swordsman, which costs no gold after the Imperial tech Forced Levy is researched. The
    Two-Handed Swordsman serve as the Malay's Skirmishers and Halberdiers counters since
    their Light Cavalry is weak, and since they cost no gold after Forced Levy is researched,
    the Two-Handed Swordsman is considered a "trash" unit. Their Skirmishers can also be used
    to counter opposing Skirmishers, although this is not as effective as the Two-Handed
    Swordsman.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Malians</name>
    <primary>Heavy Camel (Stables) or Cavalier (Stables)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Pikeman (Barracks)</support>
    <notes>The Malians have strong Stable units due to their Imperial tech Farimba, giving all their
    cavalry +5 attack. They unfortunately do not have Paladins, so Heavy Camels are their best units.
    If the enemy is not building cavalry, you can also consider going Cavaliers. As usual, cavalry
    can be countered with Halberdiers, so Skirmishers should be made to kill the Halberdiers. Since
    Malian infantry get extra pierce armor per age as well, Pikeman can also be a good units in case
    you need to counter opposing siege/archers. The Malians team bonus has their team research
    at the university 80% faster, thus they can upgrade their towers all the way to keep. If you
    want to build towers, remember to upgrade them at the University.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Mayans</name>
    <primary>Plumed Archer (Castle)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Skirmishers (Archery Range), Rams (Siege Workshop),
    Eagle Warriors (Barracks)</support>
    <notes>The Mayans have the one of the best unique unit in the game, Plumed Archers, and their
    cost is also reduced in by 10%/20%/30% per age starting from Feudal Age. As usual, make
    Halberdiers to counter opposing cavalry, and Skirmishers to counter opposing Skirmishers. While
    Plumed Archers do have a fair bit of pierce armor, they still do not fight Skirmishers very
    well. Since the Mayans do not have access to any cavalry, you'll have to do with your own
    Skirmishers as a cost-effective way to counter opposing Skirmishers. When you have an 
    excess amount of gold, consider making some Eagles as well. Mayans are VERY weak to opposing
    siege (Plumed needs to be micro excessively in order to avoid death), and Eagles can
    greatly help with that weakness.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Mongols</name>
    <primary>Mangudai (Castle)</primary>
    <support>Hussars (Stables), Skirmishers (Archery Range), Pikeman (Barracks)</support>
    <notes>Similar to the Mayans, the Mongols have great archer units in the Mangudai. The Mongols
    also have Hussars with extra HP, thus they have an effective ounter against opposing
    skirmishers. For any opposing camels or paladins, consider making some Pikeman if your
    Mangudai cannot fight back. From what I've seen from pro play though, the Mangudai can
    usually tear through Paladins given that there are enough number of Mangudais available.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Persians</name>
    <primary>Paladins (Stables) or War Elephants (Stables)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Halberdiers (Barracks)</support>
    <notes>Similar to the Huns, the Persians have great cavalry. Dissimilar to the Huns, the
    Persians' Archery Range are only decent since they lack Bracer, the last ranged units
    attack/range upgrade at the Blacksmith. Thus, it can be difficult for Persians to counter
    opposing Halberdiers with Skirmishers. Your cavalry is great though, so sheer number of
    paladins might overpower the Halberdiers. To counter opposing camels, build your fully
    upgraded Halberdiers.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Portuguese</name>
    <primary>Organ Guns (Stables)</primary>
    <support>Halberdiers (Barracks), Light Cavalry (Stables)</support>
    <notes>The Portuguese have good siege units thanks to their Imperial tech Arquebus, which
    essentially gives Ballistic to your siege units. In other words, their siege units will
    hit moving targets more accurately. You should also build Halberdiers to counter opposing
    Cavalry, and Light Cav to counter opposing mangonels.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Saracens</name>
    <primary>Heavy Camels (Stables) or Arbalests (Archery Range) or Cavalry Archers (Archery
    Range)</primary>
    <support>Skirmishers (Archery Range), Hussars (Stables)</support>
    <notes>The Saracens have a very open tech tree, which means that they can build many types
    of units. They do specialize in Camels, so that is a good choice to go for. Their Mamelukes
    are great units, however they are very costly (costs more gold than a Paladin), thus the
    Mamelukes are hard to mass. To counter opposing Halberdiers, build your own fully upgraded
    Skirmishers. To counter opposing Siege, you can build fully upgraded Hussars. Also, use
    your market excessively, as you can sell resources more efficiently than other civs, AND
    your market costs less wood as well, which can help your fast castle/slinging if that is the
    strategy you are going for.</notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Slavs</name>
    <primary></primary>
    <support></support>
    <notes></notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <primary></primary>
    <support></support>
    <notes></notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Teutons</name>
    <primary></primary>
    <support></support>
    <notes></notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Turks</name>
    <primary></primary>
    <support></support>
    <notes></notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Vietnamese</name>
    <primary></primary>
    <support></support>
    <notes></notes>
  </civ>
  <civ>
    <name>Vikings</name>
    <primary></primary>
    <support></support>
    <notes></notes>
  </civ>
</civs>